Alexandru D. Moise

Curriculum Vitae

Visiting Professor Ilia State University M +995 591 021 840 E alex.dmoise@gmail.com I am a political economist, working on the politics of social policy. I have recently obtained my PhD from Central European University's Doctoral School of Political Science, Public Policy, and International Relations. I am currently a Visiting Professor at Ilia State University's School of Arts and Sciences. My present work is focused on conceptualizing inequalities in health and understanding the social and political dynamics which drive them.

Education

PhD in Political Economy, *Central European University*, **2014–2019** Budapest, *Awarded 23.09.2019*.

Title: The Struggle for Access to Healthcare in Eastern and Southern Europe Supervisory panel: Evelyne Hübscher, Dorothee Bohle, Carsten Q. Schneider. External member for PhD defense: Ellen M. Immergut.

Visiting Fellow, Institut für die Wissenschaften vom Menschen/Institute for Human Sciences, Vienna.

Visiting Researcher, European University Institute, Florence. **2017**

M.A. in Political Economy, *Central European Univer-* **2012–2014** *sity*, Budapest, *A-*.

Title: Health Politics in Hungary and Romania

B.A. Political Science, *University of Bucharest*.

2009-2012

Publications

Forthcoming

Burlacu, Diana; Moise, Alexandru. *Romania*. In E. M. Immergut, K. M. Anderson, C. Devitt, T. Popic (Eds.), Health Politics in Europe: A Handbook. Oxford University Press. Forthcoming.

Work in Progress

Moise, Alexandru, Hübscher, Evelyne. The Conditioning Effect of Party Linkages on Attitudes on Health Care Provision. Presented at the 24th International Conference of Europeanists, Council for European Studies. Glasgow, 12-14.07.2017

Moise, Alexandru. Measuring Health Systems from a Patient Access Perspective. Presented at European Health Policy Group. 22-23.09.2016

Reviews

Moise, Alexandru. 2015. Jennifer E. Pribble: Welfare and Party Politics in Latin America. Society and Economy, vol.37.no.2/2015, pp275-278.

Moise, Alexandru. 2015. Angus Deaton: The Great Escape: Health, Wealth, and the Origins of Inequality. Sociologický asopis / Czech Sociological Review 51 (6):1105-1107

Moise, Alexandru Daniel. 2016. Joel Sawat Selway: Coalitions of the Well-being: How Electoral Rules and Ethnic Politics Shape Health Policy in Developing Countries. Sociologický asopis / Czech Sociological Review

52 (6): 1005-1008

Moise, Alexandru. 2017. Wistow, J., Blackman, T., Byrne, D., Wistow, G.: Studying Health Inequalities: An Applied Approach. Sociologický asopis, Czech Sociological Review. 2017, Vol. 53, No. 3

Media Publications

Moise, Alexandru. "Romanian Public Health System in a Continous Change" (Romanian). Available at https://www.openpolitics.ro/subiect/alegeri-2016/sanatate-2/

Professional Appointments

Max Weber Postdoctoral Fellow, European University 2020–2022 Institute, Florence.

Visiting Professor, Ilia State University, Tbilisi. 2019–2020

Teaching

Instructor - Multiple Regression Modelling, European Consortium for Political Research. **2019**

Instructor - Programming with R, European Consortium for **2019** Political Research.

Teaching Assistant - Statistics, European Con- **2016,2017,2018** sortium for Political Research.

Teaching Assistant - International Political Economy, *Central European University*. **2016**

Teaching Assistant - Quantitative Meth- 2015-2016 ods/Categorical Data Analysis, Central European University.

Research

Project Associate, *HEALTHDOX Project*, **2016–2019** Berlin/Florence.

The HEALTHDOX Project investigates the current political determinants and policy consequences of post-1989 European health reforms.

Research Assistant, *Teaching Reflexivity Project*, Central European University, Budapest.

Other Work Experience

Chair, Political Economy Research Group, Central European University. **2015-2016**

Conference Organizer, Central European University. **2015-2016**

Languages

Romanian: Native English: Proficient/C2

French/Italian/Hungarian: Beginner/A2

Software

R: proficient user - main softwareExcel: profficient userPython: beginner